Privacy Policy
==============

**Date of last revision: November 3, 2022  
**  
This “Privacy Policy” describes how Designtechnica Corporation (d/b/a Digital Trends and referred to as “we” or “us” or “our”), and our affiliated entities, collect, use, process, and share your personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy also describes your choices regarding any applicable rights of access, deletion, or correction of your personal information. We refer to personally identifiable information as “information” or “personal data” in this Privacy Policy and it means any information that can identify a person.

THIS PRIVACY POLICY INCLUDES

WHAT THIS POLICY COVERS

This “Privacy Policy” describes how Designtechnica Corporation (d/b/a Digital Trends and referred to as “we” or “us” or “our”), and our affiliated entities, collect, use, process, and share your personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy also describes your choices regarding any applicable rights of access, deletion, or correction of your personal information. We refer to personally identifiable information as “information” or “personal data” in this Privacy Policy and it means any information that can identify a person.

This Privacy Policy applies to the websites that we link to this Privacy Policy to, including without limitation, [www.digitaltrends.com](http://www.digitaltrends.com/), [www.themanual.com](http://www.themanual.com/), [www.21oak.com](http://www.21oak.com/), [www.toughjobs.com](http://www.toughjobs.com/), [www.newfolks.com](http://www.newfolks.com/), [www.happysprout.com](http://www.happysprout.com/), [www.blissmark.com](http://www.blissmark.com/), [www.pawtracks.com](http://www.pawtracks.com/), [www.DTMG.co](http://www.dtmg.co/), [www.DTadsolutions.com](http://www.dtadsolutions.com/), [es.digitaltrends.com](http://es.digitaltrends.com/), or any other website that we link this Privacy Policy to (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy also applies to information that we collect through the content we make available on third-party platforms, our marketing and engagement programs and services, our partner programs, to our branded social media pages, or when you request our newsletters, or participate in our contests, sweepstakes, or promotions.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information that we collect about employees, contractors, or job applicants. This Privacy Policy also does not apply to information that is collected by third parties, like third party websites that we may link to or promote, third party platforms or content providers, third parties that place advertisements on our Site, ad networks, affiliate marketers or affiliate marketing sites that we may link to, social media platforms or accounts, third-party service providers, widget providers. or other third-party services or applications. This Privacy Policy also does not apply to any information that is not personally identifiable, like aggregated or anonymous information.

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time and will provide notice to you as describe below in the section titled [Notice of Changes](#notice-of-changes).

Our Site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect information from individuals under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you may not use the Site or provide your information to us through the Site or otherwise. If a child under the age of 13 has provided us with their information without parental or guardian consent, the parent or guardian may contact us by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We will remove the information and unsubscribe the child from any applicable services.

If you are a citizen of Switzerland, the United Kingdom, or a country in the European Economic Area, we explain the additional rights that you may have under European privacy laws in the [European Privacy Rights](#European-Privacy-Rights) section. If you are a resident of California, Nevada, or Virginia we explain additional rights that you may have in the [U.S. Data Privacy Rights](#us-state-data-privacy-rights) section.

The Types of Information We Collect, How We Collect It & Our Business Purpose

We collect the types of information described below. We provide a summary of how we collect and use information below and more details about how we collect personal information under [Advertising and Affiliate Links](#Advertising-Affiliate-Links) and [Automatically Collected Information](#auto-collected-info). We provide more details about how we use and share information under [How we Use Information we Collect](#personal-info-collect) and [How we Share Information we Collect](#share-personal-data).  We may link, combine, or supplement the information you provide us with other information we receive from third parties to create inferences.  
‍

* **Identifiers:** : Internet protocol (IP) addresses, clickstream data, click ID, or demand side platform ID, mobile ad identifiers, customer number, unique pseudonym, or user alias. Identifiers may also include “probabilistic identifiers” or “user agents” which are means to identify an individual based upon technical characteristics of their device such as hardware address, browser type, operating system. Identifiers also includes “Unique Identifiers” which are persistent identifiers that can be used to recognize an individual or device that is linked to an individual or group of individuals, over time and across different services. We collect this information automatically when you visit and interact with the Site, click links on our Site, engage with our content, click on advertising, or open our emails. We use cookies, pixels, flash cookies or other tracking technology (explained below) (“[Automatic Tracking Technologies](#auto-collected-info)”). We use this information to identify you and to analyze how you use our Site, to improve your experience, to remember your settings, to evaluate the performance of content, advertisements, or marketing campaigns, to tailor content, advertising or marketing to you, to evaluate or analyze trends, to help our advertising or affiliate program partners provide content or advertising that is relevant to you, to administer contests, sweepstakes, or promotions, for operational or security purposes such as to administer and deliver the Site or services, or to improve our Site or services.  
    ‍
*  **Technical Information:** Connection type, settings, operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device, device identifiers, or crash data, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referrer URL, exit URL, the pages viewed (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), length of time viewed, operating system, date/time, downloads, geolocation (not precise geolocation). We collect this information automatically when you visit and interact with the Site, click links on our Site, engage with our content, click on advertising, or open our emails. We use Automatic Tracking Technologies to collect this information. We use this information to identify you and to analyze how you use our Site, to improve your experience, to remember your settings, to evaluate the performance of content, advertisements, or marketing campaigns, to tailor content, advertising or marketing to you, to evaluate or analyze trends, to help our advertising or affiliate program partners provide content or advertising that is relevant to you, to administer contests, sweepstakes, or promotions, for operational or security purposes such as to administer and deliver the Site or services, or to improve our Site or services.  
    ‍
* **Demographics:** Demographic data is generally aggregated information like age group, gender, behavior, interests, likes, or browsing or purchasing history, and may be combined with Identifiers and Technical Information. We receive this information from third parties, like ad networks, or collect it automatically when you visit the Site, click on links, engage with our content, click on advertising, or open our emails. We use this information to identify you as part of a demographic group, to analyze how you use our Site, to improve your experience, to evaluate the performance of content, advertisements, or marketing campaigns, to tailor content, advertising or marketing to you, to evaluate or analyze trends, to help our advertising or affiliate program partners provide content or advertising that is relevant to you, for operational purposes such as to administer and deliver the Site or services, or to improve our Site or services.  
    ‍
*  **Information You Provide Us:** Name, email address, phone, address, contest, sweepstakes, or promotion entry information, email communications you send us, or any other information you provide to us. We receive this information when you sign up to receive our email newsletter, enter a contest, sweepstakes, or promotion, download content from the Site, respond to a survey, provide or respond to communications, or if you share our content. We may use Automatic Tracking Technologies and collect Persistent Identifiers and Technical Information and combine it with the information you provide us. We use this information to provide our newsletters to you, to communicate with you, to administer our contests, sweepstakes, or promotions, to provide you with relevant content, to provide you with content, advertisements, offers, coupons or other deals that may be of interest to you or to otherwise fulfil the purpose for which you provided the information.  
    ‍
* **Interactions with Third Party Ads Placed on the Site:** Clickstream data, click ID, Identifiers, Technical information, privacy consent events where applicable. Third parties may place advertising on our Site, or third parties may purchase advertising through unaffiliated ad networks that appears on our Site. When you engage with advertising on our Site, we and the third-party advertiser and/or ad network collect information about you. We share that information with the third party that placed the advertisement and/or the ad network. Both we and the third party use Automatic Tracking Technologies. The third-party advertiser and/or ad network may also identify you as a visitor of a previous website or webpage and they may combine other information they collect about you. We use this information to identify you, to analyze how you use our Site, to improve your experience, to remember you and to provide you with relevant content, advertisements, offers, coupons or other deals that may be of interest to you, to help our advertising or affiliate program partners provide content or advertising that is relevant to you, and to provide and improve the Site and services.  
    ‍
* **Social Media Interactions:** Identifiers, Technical Information, name, email address, social media account information or activities (shares, likes). When you click on social media icons on our Site (e.g., to share content or like content), interact with our advertisements on social media platforms, or interact directly with our social media pages, we receive information directly from you, from the social media platform provider, and through Automatic Tracking Technology. We use information collected from social media platform providers to allow you to use the features of the social media platform (e.g., to share content with your network), to track your engagement with our Site, our social media pages, or content (such as “likes”, “shares” etc.), to understand overall engagement, to communicate with you, to analyze trends and usage patterns, or to help us improve our Site or services.  
    ‍
* **Interactions with Third Party Content Platforms:** Identifiers, Technical Information, name, email address, social media account information or activities (shares, likes). Our content may be made available through third-party platforms or applications. When you interact with our content by viewing, clicking, or sharing our content, we will receive information about you from the third-party platform provider. The third-party platform provider uses Automatic Tracking Technology to collect this information and share it with us. We use this information evaluate our content or advertising, to tailor content or advertising to you, provide you with relevant content, offers or advertising, evaluate or analyze trends, for internal operational or security purposes, to evaluate or analyze usage trends, or to improve our Site or services.  
    ‍
* **Customer Information:** Username, first name, last name, password, name, company, business address, business email phone number, limited payment information such as transaction date, time, transaction ID, account activity, Identifiers, Information You Provide Us, communications or support information, other information you provide us. Customers that purchase advertising placements directly from us are required to create an account at [www.dtadsolutions.com](http://www.dtadsolutions.com/). Creating an account requires customers to provide their personal information. We collect this information directly from you when you provide it to us, through Automatic Tracking Technology, or from third party service providers (e.g. lead generation tools). We use this information to provide services to you, to facilitate contracts or transactions with you, to support the Site and the services, for legal purposes (such as to fulfil a contract or enforce our rights), for internal business purposes, for sales and marketing purposes, or for the purposes for which you provide it.  
    ‍
* **Widgets (Ad Blockers, Push Notifications):** First name, last name, email address, browser ID, push notification ID, Identifier, and Technical Information. Third-party widgets like ad blockers and push notification functionality may be integrated with the Site. These third-party services share information with us if you engage with or use these widgets on our Site. We collect information when you interact with a widget to facilitate the features, functionality or purpose for which you provided it, and to remember you and your preferences.

### Advertising & Affiliate Links

We display content, offers, or advertisements that may be of interest to our users on the Site, or other digital properties or applications. We use Inferences (see “Identifiers” above) and demographic data to identify segments of similar users. We will provide content or advertising that may interest individuals we identify to be similar to that segment based on our Inferences. Advertisements are targeted based on information that we collect directly or that we receive from third parties (like ad networks, ad servers, or through third party affiliate marketing programs, we call these “Advertising Partners”). If we match you to a particular segment, we may provide offers, deals, content, or advertising that may be of interest to that segment, including you, and we may allow our advertising partners to better target their advertisements to that segment, including you (“Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising”). We, the third-party businesses we interact with, and our third-party service providers use the information we collect for the purposes disclosed above, but primarily to identify you and to serve relevant advertising or content to you, to analyze performance of advertisements and content, to analyze usage trends, and to target offers, promotions, deals, or content to you on the Site and elsewhere online.  

We and our Advertising Partners use Automatic Tracking Technology to collect information from you and to identify you. We will receive your information from third parties when you click through an advertisement or promotion on the Site, or when you click on an affiliate link in our content or purchase a product from an affiliate link. If you purchase product or service from an affiliate, we do not receive credit card information, or the specific items purchased.  

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any of our Advertising Partners, and we encourage you to read their privacy policies so that you understand how they process information about you.  

### Automatically Collected Information

When you visit the Site, based upon your cookie preferences, a cookie or local storage will be sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. “Cookies” and local storage are small files containing a string of characters that are sent to your computer’s browser and stored on your device when you visit a website. Cookies uniquely distinguish your web browser and keep track of information relating to serving ads on your web browser, such as the type of ads shown and the webpages on which the ads appeared. Advertising Partners place cookies on our Site and combine information they collect from our Site with other information they have independently collected across their network of websites. Advertising Partners collect and use this information under their own privacy policies. If you click on links in our content, our affiliate marketing partners use cookies to collect information about you and combine it with information they collect elsewhere.  

We use the following types of cookies on the Site for the following purposes:

‍

* **Analytics and Performance Cookies**: We use these cookies to collect information about traffic to our Site and how users use our Site. It includes the number of visitors, the websites that referred them to our Site, the pages that they visited on our Site, what time of day they visited, whether they have visited our Site before, and other similar information. We use this information to help operate our Site more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity. We also use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies (e.g., third party cookies) and provides demographic information to us.  
    ‍
* **Functional Cookies/Strictly Necessary Cookies:** These cookies are required to provide the Site and to enable you to use its features.  
    ‍
* **Social Media Cookies:** These cookies are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or “like” button on our Site or engage with our content on or through social media sites. The social media sites will record that your activities.  
    ‍
* **Targeted and Advertising Cookies:** The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to remember you when you visit our Site. Targeted cookies will track your browsing habits across websites to enable us to show advertising which is more likely to be of interest to you. These cookies use information about your browsing history to group you with other users who have similar interests. Based on that information, third-party advertisers can place cookies to enable them to show ads which we/they think will be relevant to your interests while you are on our Site. These cookies also store your location, including your latitude and longitude, which helps us/them show you locale-specific content.

### Flash Cookies

A Flash cookie is a data file placed on a device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that is built into or downloaded by you onto your device. Flash cookies are used for various purposes, including, without limitation, enabling a Flash feature and remembering your preferences. For more information about Flash and the privacy choices Adobe offers, visit [here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html). If you choose to adjust your Flash privacy settings on your device some features of the Site may not function properly.  

### Pixel Tags

We use “pixel tags,” which are small graphic files that allow us and third parties to monitor the use of the Site and collect usage data. A pixel tag can collect information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the tag appears, the URL of the page on which the pixel tag appears, the time (and length of time) the page containing the pixel tag was viewed, the type of browser that retrieved the pixel tag, and the identification number of any cookie previously placed by that server on your computer. We use pixel tags, either provided by us or by our third party advertisers, social media sites, third party affiliate partners or ad networks, to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken in connection with our Site and use them in combination with our cookies. Pixel tags also enable ad networks to serve targeted advertisements to you when you visit our Site or other websites.  

### Log Files

A log file is a file that records events that occur in connection with your use of the Site, such as your service use data.  

### Device fingerprinting

Device fingerprinting is the process of analyzing and combining sets of information elements from your device’s browser, such as JavaScript objects and installed fonts, to create a “fingerprint” of your device and uniquely identify your device and apps.  

How We Use Personal Information We Collect

We Use the information that we collect to:

‍

* provide the Site, content, or services to you.
* process transactions or communicate with you.
* provide you with information about products, services, offers, deals, or other information that is relevant to you.
* communicate with you about contests, promotions and sweepstakes, upcoming events, or other news about products and services that we or third parties may offer.
* provide you with information, products, or services that we believe will interest you, including opportunities from our third party partners.
* administer and provide contests, sweepstakes, and promotions, and to select and notify winners.
* monitor and analyze trends, usage, engagement, and other activities in connection with our Site or content.
* provide certain features or functionality to you, like enabling you to share content, enabling downloads, push notifications, or ad block features.
* Identify you, relate you to a segment, personalize the Site, content, or our services.
* provide, support, secure, monitor, and improve our Site and content.
* analyze our Site and content, support or trouble shoot issues related to our Site or content, or for other internal business purposes.
* contact you with administrative communications, including changes to terms or policies.
* send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, support or administrative messages and to respond to your comments, questions, or other messages or requests.
* detect, investigate, and prevent fraudulent transactions or other illegal or harmful activities.
* protect our or our third-party partner’s rights and property.
* protect the security or integrity of the Site or our services.
* comply with regulatory and legal obligations.
* For other purposes that may be disclosed to you at the time of collection.

HOW WE SHARE PERSONAL DATA  

We may share information as follows:

‍

* **With your Consent or To Fulfill the Purpose for Which You Provided It:** We may share your information with companies, organizations, or other third parties with your consent, or to fulfil the purpose for which you provided the information.  
    ‍
* **With Advertising Partners or Content Platforms**:  We may share information with our Advertising Partners, analytics providers, content platforms, or technology integration partners. We may share Technical Information, Identifiers, other identifiable information, or demographics and/or aggregate information with these partners. They may receive this information from their own Automatic Tracking Technologies or from our Automatic Tracking Technologies.  
    ‍

* **For Our Business Purposes:** We provide information to vendors and services providers to help us provide the Site and services, and for our business purposes. Examples of our service providers include hosting or infrastructure providers, website hosts, customer relationship management providers, email application providers, collaboration tools, lead generation tools, or other service providers.  
    ‍
* **To Market the Site or Our Partner’s Products or Services:** We may share information that you provide us with service providers who help us market our Site or services or help us to market our third-party partner’s products, services, programs, or other offers.  
    ‍
* **For Corporate Transactions:** We may share information with actual or prospective acquirers, their representatives, and other relevant participants in, or during negotiations of, any sale, merger, acquisition, restructuring, divestiture or change in control involving all or a portion of our business or assets, including in connection with bankruptcy or similar proceedings. If we undergo a sale or corporate restructure, we may disclose information to a buyer or other successor in interest.  
    ‍
* **For Legal Reasons:** We may share your information if we believe that it is necessary to comply with any court order, law, legal obligation, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request. We may also share your information if we believe that it is necessary enforce our rights (including, without limitation, our rights under the Digital Trends [Terms of Use](https://www.digitaltrends.com/terms-of-use/), the rights of our customers or users, or partners). We may share your information if we believe that disclosure of information is necessary or appropriate to protect our, our customer’s, other user’s, partner’s, or service provider’s rights or safety.  
    ‍
* ‍**With Third Party Download Providers, Widgets or Social Media Providers:** If you click on a widget or social media feature, like the Twitter “tweet” button or Facebook “like” button, or download software from our Site, the third-party provider may receive Technical Information, Identifiers, or Information You Provide Us. They may receive this information from their own Automatic Tracking Technologies or from our Automatic Tracking Technologies.

‍

* ‍**With Third Parties that We Allow to Collect Information from Our Site.** We allow certain third parties to place their own cookies or tracking technologies on our Site. The third parties authorized to collect information from our Site are: [Neustar](https://www.home.neustar/privacy), [Epsilon](https://legal.epsilon.com/global-privacy-policies/), [GrowthCode](https://drive.google.com/file/d/13qAb3iC7SLiU6x9zJjlVyBR4Sf_CzwYw/view), and [Audigent](https://audigent.com/privacypolicy/). To learn more, you can visit each third-party’s privacy policy, linked above.

Data Retention  

We retain personal information for as long as required to engage in the uses described in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required by applicable law. The criteria used to determine our retention periods include the following:

‍

* **With your Consent or To Fulfill the Purpose for Which You Provided It:**  We will retain information that you provide with consent for so long as we deem necessary to fulfill the purpose for which you provided it.  
    ‍
* **Third Party Ad Networks, Advertising Partners, or Content Platform:** We will retain information for so long as we deem necessary to the purpose for which it was collected.  
    ‍
* **For Our Business Purposes:** We will retain this information for so long as is necessary to fulfill the business purpose for which we collected the information.  
    ‍
* **To Market the Site or Our Partner’s Products or Services:** We will retain information for so long as we deem necessary to the purpose for which it was collected.

‍

* **For Legal Reasons:** we will retain information that we deem necessary to retain for legal purposes for so long as we are legally required to retain such information or for so long as it is advisable in light of our legal position (such as in regard to the enforcement of our agreements, the resolution of disputes and the applicable statute of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigation).  
    ‍

* **With Third Party Download Providers, Widgets or Social Media Providers:** We will retain information for so long as we deem necessary to the purpose for which it was collected.

Your Choices - Opting Out or Correcting Your Information  

You may choose to opt out of providing some information to us in some cases:

‍

* **Advertising:** third party services providers and/or advertisers may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You can visit [here](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1), which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members. You can opt-out of the use of your behavioral data used by DAA members to serve you interest-based advertising on third-party sites [here](https://www.aboutads.info/choices)  
    ‍
* **Google Analytics:** You may manage the information that Google Analytics receives by downloading and installing the browser plugin available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB).  
    ‍
* **Mobile Opt-Outs:** If you access the Site through an application (i.e., mobile phone or tablet) you can download the AppChoices application from your device’s application store (i.e., Google Play, Apple App Store, and Amazon Store). For more information, visit [here](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices).  
    ‍
* **Flash Cookies:** With respect to information that is collected through automated or tracking technologies, you may set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s [website](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). If you disable or refuse cookies, some parts of the Site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.

‍

* **Our Email Communications:** If you would like to opt out of receiving our email newsletter, you can opt out by sending an opt out email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email or by sending us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out only applies to the email newsletter or marketing communications, and not administrative or business communications.  
    ‍

* **Information You Provide Us**: You may send us an email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to request access to, correct, or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.

‍

* **Tracking Technologies:** You can adjust your cookie preferences, including opting out of all cookies except those that are Strictly Necessary by clicking “Manage Preferences” at the bottom of the page.

‍

* **Do Not Sell or Share My Information:** California and Virginia residents may opt-out of the sale of your information or our sharing your information for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising by clicking “Do Not Sell My Info” at the bottom of the page.

THIRD PARTY SITES & ADVERTISEMENTS  

The Site includes content or advertisements with links to third party websites and third-party widgets. These sites, services, or widgets use their own Automatic Tracking Technologies to collect data or information from you. We do not control the practices of these third parties, or their websites or content. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third parties. Please visit the privacy policies of these third parties to learn more about how they collect and use your information.

DATA SECURITY  

We take reasonable steps to protect your personal data from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, taking into due account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the information. However, no website, application, Internet, or email transmission is ever fully secure or error free, and we do not guarantee the security of any information.

INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS  

We operate in the United States. We store information in the United States. However, we and our third party partners may receive and store information globally. The information that we collect from the Site may be accessed by our employees or contractors located in other countries. Our partners or service providers may be located in other countries or may access information from other countries. By using our Site, or otherwise providing information to us, you acknowledge that your information is stored in the United States and may be accessed from other countries around the world in order to support the Site.  

The countries we transfer information to may have data protection rules that are different and less protective than those of your country. Our service providers or data processors may transfer your information to, or store or access it in, jurisdictions that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction.  

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), and your personal data is transferred outside of the EEA, we will either process your information in a territory which the European Commission has determined provides an adequate level of protection for personal information, or implement appropriate safeguards to protect your personal information, including transferring it in accordance with applicable transfer mechanism, including the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses. Please see [European Resident Privacy Rights](#European-Privacy-Rights) for more information.  

U.S. STATE DATA PRIVACY RIGHTS  

### California Resident Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, the California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA) as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA) provides you with additional rights regarding our use of your information. The rights outlined in this section do not apply to information exempted under the CCPA, including aggregated data or to individuals who are not residents of California.  

### CCPA Rights

To the extent provided under the CCPA, and subject to applicable exceptions, California residents have the following rights with respect to the information that we collect:

‍

* The right to know the categories and specific personal information we have collected, the categories and sources from which we collected the personal information, the categories of third parties with whom we share personal information, and the business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling (if applicable) personal information,
* To request a copy of the personal information that we have collected about you during the past 12 months,
* The right to opt out of sales of personal information (if applicable) or sharing personal information for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising,
* To request that we delete the personal information that we have collected from you, subject to certain exceptions,
* To correct inaccurate information that we maintain about you,
* The right to limit the disclosure of sensitive personal information, if we use or disclose sensitive personal information,
* The right to request information about and opt out of automated decision making (if applicable),
* To exercise the rights described above free from discrimination or retaliation as prohibited by the CCPA, and

### Categories of Personal Information

**For purposes of CCPA, we collect the following categories of personal information:**

‍

For the purposes of CCPA 7011(d), in the previous 12 months, we collected:

* Identifiers, such as name, unique identifier, online identifier, email address, transaction identifiers, or IP address,
* Select Information in Customer Records, such as name, email, address, or telephone number,
* Geolocation (not precise geolocation),
* Commercial Information, such as products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies,
* Internet or Network Activity,
* Professional or Employment Related Information (for job applicants only in accordance with our Job Applicant Privacy Policy), and
* Inferences from Information that Could be Used to Create a Profile, such as preferences or characteristics.

‍

We have not collected the following categories of information in the previous 12 months:

* Biometric Information, such as hair color, eye color, fingerprints, retinal scans, or thermal, olfactory, or similar information, Audio, Electronic, and Visual Information,
* Sensitive personal information (we do not collect precise geolocation)

‍

We have disclosed the following categories of information for a business purpose in the preceding 12 months:

* Identifiers: to service providers, Advertising Partners, content networks, technology partners, our online marketplace, or customers.
* Select Information in Customer Records: to service providers, Advertising Partners, content networks, technology partners, customers, or with our online marketplace.
* Geolocation (not precise geolocation): to service providers, Advertising Partners, content networks, technology partners, customers, or with our online marketplace.
* Commercial Information: to service providers and customers.
* Internet or Network Activity: to service providers, Advertising Partners, content networks, technology partners, customers, or with our online marketplace.
* Professional or Employment Related Information: to service providers.
* Inferences: to service providers, Advertising Partners, content networks, technology partners, customers, or with our online marketplace.

‍

We disclose this information for the purposes described in the following Sections: [Advertising & Affiliate Links](#Advertising-Affiliate-Links), [How We Use Information We Collect & Our Business Purpose](#types-of-info), [How We Share Information](#share-personal-data).

‍

### Sales of Personal Information, Sharing of Personal Information, Right to Opt-Out

We do not “sell” personal information as the term “sell” is traditionally understood. However, to the extent “sale” under the CCPA is interpreted to include advertising technology activities as a “sale,” we have sold or shared for Cross Contextual Behavioral Advertising purposes the following categories of information: Identifiers, Geolocation (not precise Geolocation), Internet or Network Activity, and Inferences. We provide you the option to request that we not “sell” or “share” your personal information. We sell or share this information with our Advertising Partners or customers.

‍

We do not collect information about user’s age. Where we receive demographic information from third parties, we receive age ranges. Therefore, we do not have actual knowledge of collection of information from individuals under the age of 16 and do not have actual knowledge of sales of information of individuals under the age of 16.

‍

To the extent we sell or share your personal information as those terms are defined under the CCPA, you have the right to opt-out of the sale or sharing of your personal information by us to third parties at any time. You may submit a request to opt-out of by clicking [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.digitaltrends.com/do-not-sell-my-info/). You may also submit a request to opt-out by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### Collection of Sensitive Personal Information

We do not collect sensitive personal information as that term is defined by the CCPA.  

### Virginia Resident Privacy Rights

If you are a Virginia resident, the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (VCDPA) provides you with additional rights regarding our use of your information. The rights outlined in this section do not apply to information exempted under the VCDPA, including aggregated data, or to individuals who are not residents of Virginia.

‍

We describe the Information We Collect, How We Use Personal Information, and How We Share Personal Information above. We describe how we use personal information for targeting or advertising in our Affiliate Links & Advertising Section. We do not collect sensitive personal information as that term is defined by the VCDPA.

‍

To the extent provided under the VCDPA, and subject to applicable exceptions, Virginia residents have the following rights with respect to the information that we collect:

‍

* To know the personal information that we process about you,
* To access personal information that we process about you,
* To correct inaccurate information that we maintain about you,
* To obtain a copy of the personal information that we have collected about you,
* The right to opt out of the processing of personal information for (i) targeted advertising, (ii) the sale of personal data, or (iii) profiling for decisions with legal or other significant effects on the consumer.
* To request that we delete the personal information that we have collected from you, subject to certain exceptions,
* To exercise the rights described above free from discrimination or retaliation as prohibited by the VCDPA, and

‍

To the extent “sale” under the VCDPA is interpreted to include advertising technology activities as a “sale,” we have sold the following categories of information: Identifiers, Geolocation (not precise geolocation), Internet or Network Activity, and Inferences. We sell or share this information with our Advertising Partners or customers. You may submit a request to opt-out of by clicking [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.digitaltrends.com/do-not-sell-my-info/). You may also submit a request to opt-out by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### Financial Incentives

Financial incentives are programs, benefits, or other offerings, including payments to consumers as compensation, for the disclosure, deletion, or sale of personal information about them. We do not offer financial incentives in exchange for information. If you use an ad blocker to restrict our collection of information about you, we may not allow you to access the content on our Site. We are able to provide the Site and services to you by allowing advertisers to target advertisements to our visitors.  

### Exercising Your CCPA or VCDPA Rights

California residents may exercise CCPA rights and Virginia residents may exercise their VCDPA rights by contacting us by phone or email as indicated in [the Contacting Digital Trends](#contacting-dt) section below. Your rights may only be exercised by you or by your designated agent. You may submit a CCPA request to know twice within a 12-month period.  

Your request must include enough information to allow us to reasonably verify that you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative, which may include: (1) verifying your account information if you have an account with us, or (2) requesting two forms of identification that are reliable for verification purposes, unless the request includes sensitive information and, in which case, we may require three forms of verification and a signed declaration. The information included in your request must allow us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.  

We cannot respond to your request if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm that the personal information relates to you. If we cannot verify your identity or authority, we will not fulfill your request. We will only use personal data provided in the request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make it.  

You may submit a request through a designated agent. You must instruct that agent that they will need to state that they are acting on your behalf when making the request, have reasonably necessary documentation, and be prepared to provide the necessary personal information to identify you in our database.  

### California Shine the Light Disclosure

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83- 1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer data which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for their own direct marketing purposes and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: 111 SW 5th Ave Ste 1000, Portland, OR 97204.  

Nevada Resident Privacy Rights  

If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt out of the sale of certain information to third parties who intend to license or sell that information. You can exercise this right by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with the subject line “**Nevada Do Not Sell Reques**t” and providing us with your name and the email address.  

European Resident Privacy Rights  

If you are a resident of Switzerland, the United Kingdom, or a country within the European Economic Area (EEA), you may have rights under European data protection laws regarding the processing of your information. You have the right to access the information that we hold about you and, in some cases, to ask that your information be corrected, erased, or transferred (subject to limitations in applicable law). You may also have the right to object to or request that we restrict the processing of your information. If we collected information based on your consent, you have the right to revoke your consent.  

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, you may contact us as indicated in the Contacting Digital Trends section below. The rights may not apply in some cases, including where providing access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or where it would violate the rights of a third party. We may request specific information from you to confirm your identity. In some cases, we may charge a reasonable fee for access to your information.  

You may file a complaint with a [data protection authority](https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/our-role-supervisor/complaints_en). The data protection authority will require you to first attempt to resolve any complaint with us. Please see [Contacting Digital Trends](#contacting-dt) below to file a complaint with us.    

With respect to the information that we collect or process as a result of your use or interaction with the Site, we may be considered a joint controller with our third-party partners (e.g. ad networks, analytics providers or affiliate marketers). Third party partners that are joint controllers as a result of the information that they receive, collect and process from the Site are responsible for obtaining any necessary consent and/or ensuring that they have a lawful basis for processing personal information.  

Where we collect information for our own purposes, like when we collect information when you visit the Site, when you interact with our social media pages, email newsletters or other marketing, sign up for a contest, or the information that we collect about your use of the Site, Digital Trends is the “data controller.” Our lawful basis for collecting this information is with your consent, to fulfill contracts, our legitimate interest in providing the Site and content to you, or to comply with our legal obligations.  

We will retain information for as long as necessary to fulfill our legitimate business purpose, to comply with any laws or regulations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. We may retain information longer for our legitimate business interest if retention is not outweighed by your personal rights and freedoms.  

DISPUTE RESOLUTION  

You may direct questions or complaints arising from this Privacy Policy to us by contacting us through the channels indicated in the [Contacting Digital Trends](#contacting-dt) section below. Residents of the EEA and Switzerland may file a complaint with a data [protection authority](https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/our-role-supervisor/complaints_en). The data protection authority will require you to first attempt to resolve any complaint with us, please see [Contact Digital Trends](#contacting-dt) below to file a complaint with Digital Trends.  

Any other disputes arising out of or related to this Privacy Policy will be handled in accordance with the dispute resolution process indicated in our [Terms of Use](https://www.dtmg.co/terms-of-use).  

NOTICE OF CHANGES  

The Site and our business may change from time to time. As a result, we may make changes to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on this page and will indicate at the top of this page the date these terms were last revised. If we make material changes, we will notify you, either through a pop up on the Site, in an email notification, or through other reasonable means. Your continued use of the Site after the date any such notice constitutes your acceptance of the modifications.  

CONTACTING DIGITAL TRENDS  

If you have any questions or comments about this notice, the ways in which we collect and use your information, your choices or rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

**TollFree Phone:** [1-888-914-9661](tel:1-888-914-9661)

**Email:** [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Postal Address:** 111 SW 5th Ave Ste 1000, Portland, OR 97204

**Data Protection Officer:** Nathan Bell; [\[email protected\]](https://www.dtmg.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  

CHANGE LOG  

### Date of Change:

May 13, 2021  

### Description of Change:

No change to the types of information collected or the processing activities. Annual update to the Privacy Policy to address legal and regulatory changes, including more specificity regarding processing activities.  
  
Updates include providing more detail  about the categories of information we collect, the purposes for which we  collect information and the third parties with whom we share information. Changes to restructure the Policy and make the statement easier for readers  to navigate.  
  
Updates include specific information with  respect to CCPA rights and legal processes related to the CCPA, and the  rights of EU citizens.    

May 25, 2021  

Updates to provide more clarity about how we share information with third-party ad networks, advertising partners, and content platforms.  
‍  

June 23, 2022  

No change to the types of information collected or the processing activities. Annual update to the Privacy Policy to address legal and regulatory changes.  

Work  
with us.
===============

Businesses and agencies of all sizes can now reach the world’s most sought-after audiences through Digital Trends Media Group’s portfolio of sites and network of partners.

© 2022 Digital Trends Media Group, a Designtechnica Company. All Rights Reserved.
